Douglas J. Lawrence

San Francisco Bay Area, CA | 323-806-4865 | douglasjlawrence@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/douglas-lawrence | Github: github.com/lawrend | pronouns: he/his/him

Software Engineer

Full Stack Web Developer with experience in Ruby, Java, Python, and JavaScript frameworks. With a background as an educator and attorney, I come to coding guided by logic and creativity. I strive to translate user stories into feature-rich, maintainable code and tenaciously solve the puzzles every project surely provides. When there is a question, ask me; I may not know the answer, but I'll know where to find it.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, React, Redux, CSS, HTML, Git, GitHub

Experience: Python, Java, SQL, UNIX, Sinatra, Burp Suite, WireShark, Adobe Premiere, Final Draft

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

endangered - <u>Github</u> | <u>Walkthrough</u> | <u>Try it</u> (give it a minute to load--Heroku apps are like that) Explore protected wildlife habitats and the species that live there.

Built front end using React/Redux and incorporating Semantic UI

- Developed Rails API back end to handle data persistence and respond to fetch requests.
- Integrated fetch requests to 3 APIs Google Maps, Wikipedia, and Enigma
- App deployed to Heroku

Payam with JS - <u>Github</u> | <u>Walkthrough</u> | <u>Try it</u> and use account: '<u>guest@guest.com</u>' password: 'password' Collaboratively construct a poem -- based on the Surrealists' game, Exquisite Corpse.

- Designed front end with Bootstrap and custom CSS
- Implemented user authentication with the Devise and OAuth gems
- Configured RESTful Rails API with ActiveModel Serializer

Event Planner - Github | Walkthrough

Sinatra-based event planner.

- Utilized Sinatra, ActiveRecord, and SQLite to create simple and clean event planner
- Included user accounts and input validations

EDUCATION

City College of San Francisco (ongoing), San Francisco, CA, 2016 - Present

Ongoing technical coursework includes Java, Python, Data Structures & Algorithms, Network Security, and Ethical Hacking

Flatiron School, 2018 - 2020

Software Engineering--Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React/Redux

Berkeley Law School, University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Juris Doctor (J.D.), Law

Coe College, Cedar Rapids, IA

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Philosophy, Phi Beta Kappa

SELECTED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LSAT Instructor/Tutor, TestMasters, San Francisco Bay Area, CA, 2003 - Present

- Teach the principles of formal argumentation and critical thinking to college graduates and working professionals
- Provide intensive instruction one-on-one, to small groups, and to full lecture halls
- Break down concepts to make them understood by individuals from a wide range of backgrounds

Attorney, Gonzalez & Leigh, San Francisco, CA, 2010 - 2012

- Served as trial and appellate counsel in civil rights and commercial litigation in federal and state court.
- Tried a three-week jury trial in state court; assisted in jury selection, witness preparation, and exhibit management; conducted depositions; drafted pleadings and discovery requests.